# **Choyo Matsuta**

Home Address Harbor City, CA 90710, USA Cell (714) 875-7913 Email cmatsuta@hotmail.com

## Summary

Professional ERP consultant and system architect who has ability to assist in designing ERP business software systems. Hands on experience in operations using Microsoft ERP system such as Dynamics GP and Dynamics 365 FO, BC and Sales , Power platform and also implementing Shopify API. Have the necessary expertise to develop business and accounting software to help facilitate the business operations of clients. Will to consult with engineering stuff to evaluate interface between hardware and software, develop specifications and performance requirements and resolve customer problems.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Japan Business Systems Technology** Torrance, CA Sep., 2011 - Current **Sr ERP System Consultant / Assistant Manager** 

- Configure fully integrated ERP system for over 50 companies
- Conducted ERP business assessment and requirement analysis as project leader.
- Assisted customers to solve issues related with ERP system and related modules.
- Maintained and coordinated proposed designs for ERP system releases.
- Lead new functions and features and help improving team skills.

## Calsoft Systems, Torrance, CA Nov., 2009 – Sep., 2011

## **Accounting Operation Support**

- Assisted internal accounting and operation tasks.
- Assisted manager with closing process and prepared monthly Work in Progress reports.
- Provided high quality helpdesk support by troubleshoot telephonically or emailing with customers in both English and Japanese and document help desk requests and resolutions.
- Create or revise user instructions, procedures, or manuals.
- Prepared training and workflow documentations.
- Test developed software.

## **EDUCATION**

#### UCR Extension Web development, July 2020 - Current

Activities and Societies: The Coding Boot Camp at UCR Extension covers a full-stack curriculum, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Git, and more.

#### Bachelor of Arts - Business Administration, May 2008

Major: Accounting

California State University, Fullerton, CA

Bachelor of Science - Business Administration, May 2006

Grossmont College, El Cajon, CA

### RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Links to deployed app: https://cmatsuta.github.io/myportfolio/portfolio.html

#### RECOGNITIONS

Recognized as an outstanding CSUF student July 2006.

#### **SKILLS**

## Languages:

Speak, read and write English and Japanese

#### Other:

Active communication skills

Ability to interact with a wide variety of cultures

Teamwork and ability to relate to and lead people

Motivate, hardworking, and reliable

Ability to contribute and convey thoughts and ideas to others effectively

Able to adapt to change

## **Qualifications Summary**

Microsoft Dynamics AX Financials, Microsoft Dynamics AX Trade and Logistics, Microsoft Dynamics GP Integration Manager, Microsoft Dynamics GP Financials